lm.com 2011-04-23

# Kiva - Privacy Policy

  1. Kiva will not rent or sell your personal information to third parties. 

  2. When you create an account on Kiva, we collect basic information about you through the registration process - your name, email address, and a means to authenticate your account (for example, a password). You may also provide additional information through the account creation process, such as the email address of the person who referred you to Kiva. You may also provide other information (for example, a picture of yourself, a picture of your lending team, your occupation, your physical address, your city/state/ country of residence, the reasons why you choose to lend on Kiva) through the creation of a public profile page, creating/joining a lending team page on the Website, making a loan transaction on Kiva, updating your account information, or by registering with Kiva through a third-party single sign on registration tool. A basic public profile page will automatically be created for you when you register for a account at Kiva, which shows your Kiva lender page profile url and the date on which you joined Kiva. You have the option of closing down your public profile page by changing your profile option to anonymous at your discretion. To the extent you maintain the public profile, once you begin to conduct transactions or utilize the features/functionality on Kiva (e.g., make a microloan, invite others to participate in Kiva, purchase a Kiva Card as a gift), your public profile will also show the following information: the loans you have made, the lending teams you have joined, your city/state/country of residence and the individuals who have accepted your invitations to create an account on Kiva. Kiva will also track information on your microloan transactions (for example, amount of the loan, recipient of the loan) and make that information available to you on your private Kiva account page. If you have a public lender profile page, such lending information may furthermore be shared in public areas of the Kiva website. Kiva will also collect information on any donations you make to Kiva via the website and communicate with you (for example, to provide donation confirmations) via the email address and/or the physical address that you provide. 

  3. As you use additional features of the Website, we may collect the additional information you enter. If you purchase a Kiva Card gift product, we collect information about your purchase (for example, your name as purchaser, amount you spent, number of Kiva Cards purchased) and information about your recipient that you provide (for example, recipient name, email address, physical address) in order to deliver the Kiva Card, contact the purchaser and/or the recipient with respect to the purchased items, and note the recipient's relation to the purchaser. If you use interactive features on Kiva to write a comment - for example, on a Kiva Fellows journal - Kiva will collect your name, email address, any url address you enter, and your comment - and publicly display the information (except for your email address). If you use interactive features on Kiva to indicate that you "like" a particular feature or listing on Kiva, that information will be collected and will be noted on the Kiva website that you have "liked" that feature or listing and that information may furthermore be shared on applicable third party social networking sites to which you may have authorized such information sharing. If you contact Kiva Customer Service, we will collect the information you provide (for example, your name, email address, physical address, phone number, question/comment) in order to contact you and address your question or comment. If you submit an application to Kiva, such as via the Website's Kiva volunteer portal, we collect the information you submit (for example, name, phone number, resume, cover letter, position of interest) to assess the application and follow up with you on such submission. 

  4. By establishing an account on Kiva, you agree to receive emails or other written communication, such as physical mail, based on your account status or activity (for example, confirmations of loans you have made, confirmation receipts for donations you have made, notifications of loan repayments you have received, statements or other information with respect to the amount of credit available in your Kiva account, confirmation of email address or password changes, or customer service inquiries regarding the status of or activity in your account). 

  5. By default, you will receive update emails on your loans that are sent by our field partners through the Website. Kiva will not disclose your email address to our field partners in any case -- these emails are sent through a webform without any third party learning your address. You can choose not to receive these emails through a preference on the Website. 

  6. By default, you may receive periodic newsletter emails from Kiva. The frequency of these newsletters may vary. You can choose not to receive these newsletters through a preference on the Website. 

  7. Kiva will not disclose your personally identifiable lending activity to any third party without consent (please note: the creation of a public lender profile on Kiva is considered consent for such disclosure). Kiva reserves the right to record and display anonymous lending activity on the Website and display the general regions where our lenders are located. 

  8. Kiva's service providers, agents and representatives may be provided access to your personally identifiable information as part of, or incident to, their provision of services to Kiva (for example, processing of microloan transactions). All such access shall be under appropriate confidentiality agreements and limited to use to provide services to Kiva. 

  9. If you follow any links which remove you from the Website (including, but not limited to, the independently operated KivaStore.org, Kiva CafePress, KivaFriends.org, and PayPal), this Privacy Policy no longer applies - i.e., Kiva does not control the privacy policies or the privacy practices of any third parties and use of those third party sites are governed by those third party sites' respective terms of use and privacy policies. Please note that payment processing for (i) additions of funds into a Kiva account or (ii) withdrawal of funds from a Kiva account is provided by the third-party payment processing provider, PayPal. 

  10. Similar to many websites, if a Website user has enabled cookies in their browser, Kiva, independently and through enabled third party tools and programs, collects certain technical information utilizing a cookie file, such as the path of users to the Website, pages visited, originating IP address, browser type, browser language, and the date and time of the user's visit. This information helps Kiva track trends and improve areas of our Website based on visits, and are common analytics used by most websites. 

  11. This Website is intended to be used by adults. It is not intended for children, and Kiva does not want to collect any personal information for users who are under the age of 13\. Kiva recommends that parents do not post, or permit others to post, any personally identifiable information with respect to persons under the age of 13. 

  12. Kiva may update or modify this Privacy Policy from time to time. If any changes are made, Kiva will reflect the date on which any such changes are made and posted by updating the "last updated" date at the top of the page. Please be sure to check this page periodically for changes. This Privacy Policy was last changed and posted on our Website on January 26, 2011. 

  13. We take privacy seriously and we value yours.
